Alright, why did we choose a Python shell job?
If you look at this, it shows Python shell. Why Python?
Shell and why not Glue's Park job?
Because it's a Python script.
All we're doing is just pulling the data, okay?
So you look at the script and I highly encourage you to kind
of use amazing queue to understand what is going on here.
Of course, I've provided the script to you,
but that doesn't mean you simply blindly use it.
Use as in Q and and chat with it. Understand the script.
What is being done here? So this is a Python script
and we can simply download the data from the cloud
front URL.
Again, the cloud front URL is all discussed in the
Agent D AI course.
I hope you've done that already. Alright, the next step,
now H-V-F-H-V.
Uh, this now has a lot of data. Right?
Before we had just had one file here.
Remember we deleted that file.
So now that we have more data, so this blue catalog table
has to know about the data that we have here.
Now, before we had just one Parquet file,
which I'll erase it now, but now we have a lot of data.
So this table needs to know that there is a lot of data now.
So we have to use a crawler
and crawl over this location again.
So we'll go back to the glue, we'll click on this bug bar,
we'll scroll down, right click open a new tab.
The crawler console is now open
and our crawler is right here.
We'll click on this and we'll simply run that.
But before we run that, let me show you the table itself.
Okay? Lemme just go back to databases, right?
Click open in a new tab
and then go to our database, which is uh,
mission D-H-H-O-F-N-Y-C-T-L-C.
And that we have one table here.
If you look at the table, lemme click on the table here.
We scroll down. Do you see any partition here? No.
It says you have run any partition,
but we now have data which is in, which is partition, right?
We now have data just partition here.
So obviously the table metadata
doesn't have the information.
Okay? And this is why, this is why we need to crawl
this location again so that this table gets
information about the partition.
So the metadata gets updated.
I hope this clear on metadata is data about the data, right?
The structure about the data.
So now we'll run this, we'll go back
to the crawler and we'll run it.
But remember, this organization,
this partitioning is something which you had decided, okay?
'cause it is the best practice.
So when you wrote the script using Agent TKI, you made sure
that data will get loaded into data lake
in a partition format like this.
Let me go back to crawler. It is all finished.
Now we'll go back to the table.
And if I just now refresh this right here,
you should see the partitions.
This might take about a minute or two to show up here.
Don't fret. If you don't see it immediately,
it'll take about a minute or so.
And if you click on the view files,
it'll exactly take you to the exact
Partition it took me to month zero one partition.
In fact. So this added a lot of partitions,
22 partitions here.
Okay? Because we had how many, we had 12 here.
And if you go to 2025, we had 10 here.
So 22 partitions we have.
And so we see 22 partitions right here in fact.
And you can also look at the crawler log as well.
If you go to the crawler run here
and click on view CloudWatch logs, you can see that right?
Right here when I expand this,
the crawler created the partition with values.
All of this for this table in database mission,
DHF, university LC.
So now when you go back to the table and click on actions
and view data, it'll take you to Athena.
And now on the Athena console here,
it shows you partitioned right here.
Expand this. It'll show you that you have the table
as partitioned by year and month here.
Now if you get this error like this, make sure
that you have output location defined.
So if you go to query settings here
and uh, manage, make sure you add the bucket.
The bucket's gonna be named as mission dh. Okay?
We gotta have the previous year as well, S3
S3 colon slash slash and the bucket name.
And this bucket is the one that got created, especially
for the saving the Athena query results.
Okay? So this was created with the help
of the script you ran before as well.
So make sure that you use this bucket itself.
Athena query results one and then save it.
Okay, I got an error here.
Uh, I think I have to use a small less. There you go.
Now I can just save it. It's all done. Go back to editor.
So now if you wanna just query this,
all you can do is simply just add a filter where
your equal to, let's say in single codes
20, 25
and month equal to let's say in single codes zero two.
And then, so this is how the analysts can run queries
on the lake with the appropriate filters.
This will also help the queries run a lot faster
because you are simply gonna be scanning just the data in
these two partitions alone.
Now in the next video, we have to now create one more table
for the zone table and then we can hand over the tables
to the data analyst for further analysis.